

42, Hankinson Road, Bournemouth, BH9 1HW, UK

□ (+44) 07732563454 | ■ liwang1991@outlook.com | ★ www.alibabade.github.io | ᡚ alibabade | 🛅 - -66367613b

## **Summary**\_

A PhD candidate on Computer Vision and Computer Graphics at National Centre for Computer Animation, Bournemouth University, UK. My research focuses on image/video based neural style transfer, in particular, photographic style transfer and coherent video style transfer for arbitrary artistic styles using deep learning techniques. I received my M.Eng and B.Sci degrees from Department of Computer Science at Jilin University China in 2016 and 2013, respectively. Then I got a 4-year PhD scholarship from Bournemouth University and China Scholarship Council.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Sensor ID Campobasso, Italy

Software Engineer

 Developed a software for real-time monitoring and recording sensor data. The software is developed in python (e.g., tkinter, and matplotlib) but transformed into a single .EXE file without any python dependencies.

**ITware**Budapest, Hungary

CONSULTANT ON AI TECHNIQUES

Aug. 2019 - Sep. 2019

Sep. 2019 - Oct. 2019

- · Gave representations about Recommendation System (RS) in Machine Learning and Deep Learning area.
- Helped to design a potential customized deployment of RS for European iGame Project.

IBM(China) Ltd

Beijing, China

INTERN R&D PROGRAMMER

Jan. 2013 - May. 2013

- Developer for an intranet office product and dealt with product bugs.
- Built various Windows/Linux systems for teammates to test product performance on different OS platforms.

# **Projects**

### **OPEN SOURCE CODE for Energy Expenditure through two inertial sensors**

Malaga, Spain

RESEARCH & SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Oct. 2019 - Feb 2020

- Research problems & motivation: 1. It's difficult to reproduce energy expenditure estimation for human physical activities proposed in related researches; 2. Enclosed commercial software is way too expensive for clinical practises.
- Solutions: 1. Describe a clear procedure of physical activity monitoring and data analysis (including hardware settings like chip models and total information of participants); 2. Develop a complete open-source code of calculating Energy Expenditure for physical activities based on low-cost inertial sensors.

## Bas-relief Modelling from Enriched Detail and Geometry with Deep Normal Transfer

Bournemouth, UK

RESEARCH

Jun. 2018 - Jan 2020

- Motivation: artistic creation of geometry details on digital bas-reliefs should be more enriched and preserved well under various situations like over-compression and curved surfaces.
- Methodology: 1. propose a semantic neural normal transfer to enrich the details; 2. propose a normal decomposition to enhance the geometry preservation by for digital bas-reliefs.
- · Result: our approach beats the SOTA methods by producing more vivid geometry details and better geometry preservation.

### **Coherent Video Style Transfer for Arbitrary Artistic Styles**

Bournemouth, UK

RESEARCH

RESEARCH

Nov. 2017 - Aug 2019

- Research problem: 1. style transformation is sensitive to small variants (e.g., lighting, noises and motions) among video frames, which causes flickering problem. 2. ghosting artefacts and blurriness artefacts need to be fixed; 3. no single network for arbitrary artistic styles.
- Methodology: 1. choose more stable optimisation-based approach as baseline network, which is naturally made for arbitrary styles; 2. propose mask techniques for preventing ghosting artefacts and sharpness loss for preventing blurriness artefacts.
- Result: our approach beats the SOTA methods by qualitative and quantitative evaluation on both popular MPI Sintel and Davis 2017 datasets.

### **Fast Photographic Style Transfer**

Bournemouth, UK

Apr. 2017

• Research problem: distortion occurs on both content reconstruction and style transformation stage.

- Methodology: 1. propose two streams CNN models for separate content reconstruction and style transformation; 2. propose similarity loss to enhance the distribution matching between content image and reference image; 3.To speed up the transfer process, we integrate similarity loss into feed-forward networks.
- Result: 1. we beat a cvpr SOTA method on qualitative evaluation and user study; 2. our approach eventually speedups the transformation process over 100 times.

Honors & Awards	
DOMESTIC	
<ul> <li>China Council Scholarship, Department of Education, China</li> <li>Huawei Scholarship, Jilin University</li> <li>National Postgraduate Scholarship, Jilin University</li> <li>National Encouragement Scholarship, Jilin University</li> </ul>	Beijing, China Changchun, China Changchun, China Changchun, China
Education	
National Centre for Computer Animation, Bournemouth University PHD IN COMPUTER SCIENCE	Bournemouth, UK Sep. 2016 - present
Department of Computer Science and Technique, Jilin University  M.E. AND B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING	Changchun, China Sep. 2009 - Jun. 2016
Selected publications	
OPEN SOURCE CODE for Energy Expenditure through two inertial sensors  Wang, L*, Martín-Martín J.*, De-Torres I., Escriche-Escuder A, Gonzalez-Sanchez M., Muro-Culebras A.,	Malaga, Spain
Roldán-Jiménez C., Ruiz-Munőz M., Mayoral-Cleries F., Biró A., Tang W., Nikolova B., Salvatore A., Cueta-Bargas A.I.	Feb. 2020
<ul> <li>* indicates equal contribution. under review. submitted to Journal of Applied Physiology</li> </ul>	
Bas-relief Modelling from Enriched Detail and Geometry with Deep Normal Transfer  Meili Wang*, Li Wang*, Tao Jiang, Nan Xiang, Mingqiang Wei, Xiaosong Yang, Taku Komura, Jianjun Zhang  • * indicates equal contribution. under review. submitted to Neuralcomputing.	Bournemouth, UK Jan. 2020
Fast Coherent Video Style Transfer	Bournemouth, UK
<b>LI WANG</b> , XIAOSONG YANG, WEIDONG MIN, JIANJUN ZHANG  • under review. submitted to IEEE transactions on Multimedia.	Aug. 2019
Fast photographic style transfer based on convolutional neural networks	Bintan, Indonesia
• Proceedings of CGI 2018.	Jun. 2018
Photographic Style Transfer	Bournemouth, UK
LI WANG, ZHAO WANG, XIAOSONG YANG, SHI-MIN HU, JIANJUN ZHANG  • The Visual Computer.	Nov. 2018

## Personal Skills & Hobbies \_\_\_\_\_

• Proceedings of CASA 2019.

since 2009 **Ubuntu/Windows**, Python, C/C++, Matlab, Torch/PyTorch since 2013 **Badminton**, Speed skating

Nan Xiang, **Li Wang**, Tao Jiang, Yanran Li, Xiaosong Yang, Jianjun Zhang

Single-image Mesh Reconstruction and Pose Estimation via Generative Normal Map

Computer Skills Hobbies

Paris, France

Jul. 2019

FEBRUARY 9, 2020 LI WANG · RÉSUMÉ 2